Harvard University. Corporation. Records of land and property owned by Harvard University, 1643-1835: an inventory
Records of land and property owned by Harvard University, 1643-1835
- VII. Maine / "Eastern lands," 1690-1835, 1.62 cubic feet (2.5 document boxes and 23 oversize folders)
  - C. Bridgton, 1780-1807
    - Letter from James Emerson to Jonathan Jackson requesting that he sell Bridgton lot to Elias Barry, Oct. 20, 1807, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 52
  - D. Pownalborough, 1780-1833
    This subseries contains records related to College land in Pownalborough, later called Wiscasset, The land, once called “Governor Pownal’s lot,” was sold to Joseph Christophers in 1780 because the previous owner failed to pay his taxes. In 1784, Harvard purchased the land from Christophers, and in 1829 the University sold the lot to Elisha Meservey. Records include correspondence, a conveyance, a Harvard Corporation vote, a quitclaim deed, and receipts.
    - Conveyance of land in Pownalborough to Joseph Christophers, performed by constable Abraham Nason, May 8, 1780, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 53
      Signed by Abraham Nason, Nathaniel Theving(?), Jim Langdon; addenda made June-August 1780 by Jim Langdon, Jonathan Bowman, and Joseph Christophers.
    - Letter from Jonathan Bowman to James Bowdoin about land in Pownalborough, May 12, 1784, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 54
    - Quitclaim deed for "Governor Pownall's lot" in Pownalborough, from Joseph Christophers to the President and Fellows of Harvard College, July 15, 1784, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folders 55 and 56
      Folders contain the original, signed deed and a manuscript copy of the deed.
    - Letter from Thomas Rice to Ebenezer Storer about Pownalborough land, Sept. 22, 1789, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 57
    - Letter from Alden Bradford to Ebenezer Storer about the value of the Pownalborough land, April 3, 1794, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 58
    - Letter from Hezekiah Packard to Eliphalet Pearson about the College land in Pownalborough, Jan. 6, 1803, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 59
    - Corporation vote empowering Silas Lee to sell the Pownalborough land on behalf of Harvard, April 20, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 60
    - Draft of letter from Jonathan Jackson to Silas Lee about Pownalborough land, April 23, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 61
    - Letter from Theophilus Parsons to Jonathan Jackson, Sept. 7, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 62
    - Manuscript copy of quitclaim deed for Pownalborough land to Elisha Meservey, May 11, 1829, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 13
      Elisha Meservey paid $400 for the lot.
    - Mortgage deed, Elisha Meservey to Harvard College for Pownalborough land, May 11, 1829, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 63
    - Edmund T. Bridge’s bill for work related to Pownalborough land, June 1829, and letter to Ebenezer Francis, June 13, 1829, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 64
    - Letter from Thomas Wren Ward to Nathaniel Bowditch, May 5, 1831, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 65
    - Letter from Edmund T. Bridge to Nathaniel Bowditch, May 9, 1831, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 66
    - Letter from Bradbury Bridge to Nathaniel Bowditch, Aug. 11, 1831, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 67
    - Letter from Bradbury Bridge (to Nathaniel Bowditch?), Aug. 19, 1831, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 68
    - Receipt, Thomas Wren Ward to Nathaniel Bowditch, Aug. 30, 1831, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 69
    - Letters from Bradbury Bridge to Nathaniel Bowditch, Dec. 29, 1831; Jan. 14, 1832; Dec. 3, 1832; March 19, 1833; and July 8, 1833, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 70
    - Receipt, Thomas Wren Ward to Nathaniel Bowditch, July 11, 1833, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 71
  - E. Miscellaneous lands, 1785-1835
    Records in this subseries pertain to an array of lots in Maine owned by Harvard. Some of the records are here because there is an insufficient quantity of records (or information about them) to constitute a distinct subseries, and other records are here because they pertain to land in multiple locations. Records include correspondence, memoranda, and copies of votes and meeting minutes.
    - Manuscript copy of minutes and descriptions related to “Eastern” lands, 1762-1785, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 72
      Annotation on verso: “B. Guild’s extracts as returned by him March 1809”
    - Corporation request for information about Shapleigh land, ca. Sept. 1787, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 73
    - Letter from Benjamin Chadbourn to Ebenezer Storer about Shapleigh land, Oct. 22, 1787, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 74
    - Manuscript copy of Harvard Corporation vote authorizing Eliphalet Pearson to inquire about the state of College lands in Maine, Feb. 10, 1801, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 75
    - Letter from Daniel Stowell to Eliphalet Pearson about College lands in Paris, May 16, 1801, and Pearson’s memorandum about the lands, ca. 1801, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 76
    - Letter from John Abbott to Eliphalet Pearson about Maine census and land values, as well as unrelated personal and political matters, May 23, 1801, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 77
    - Letter from Abijah Warren to the Trustees of Harvard College requesting to purchase Paris land, Dec. 1, 1801, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 78
    - Letter from Michael Little to Eliphalet Pearson about College lands in Poland, Dec. 5, 1801, and memorandum about the lands, ca. 1801, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 79
    - Letter from Josiah Pierce to Eliphalet Pearson about College lands in Baldwin (formerly Flintstown), April 8, 1802 and Pearson’s memorandum about the land, ca. 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 80
    - Letter from Josiah Russell to Ebenezer Storer about purchasing College land in Bethel, Aug, 18, 1802 and Pearson’s memorandum about the land, ca. 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 81
    - Eliphalet Pearson’s notes about College lands in Raymond, Rumsford, Sedgwick, Trenton, Waterford, Otisfield, Penobscot, and Castine, ca. 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 82
    - Eliphalet Pearson’s notes about College lands in Goldsborough, Jay, and Lovell, ca. 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 83
    - Two small notebooks containing Eliphalet Pearson’s reports on College lands throughout Maine, ca. 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 84
      Also includes loose memorandum about “Marsh No. VI.”
    - Letter from Thomas Perley to the Harvard Corporation about David Potter’s offer to buy College lot in Baldwin (formerly Flintstown), Feb. 8, 1803, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 85
    - Letter from John Lee to Eliphalet Pearson requesting to purchase College land in Orland, Feb. 15, 1803, and Pearson’s memorandum about the land, ca. 1803, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 86
    - Manuscript copy of resolves related to “Eastern” lands, 1784-1803, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 87
    - Letter from Supply Belcher to Eliphalet Pearson about College lands in Tyngstown (later Wilton), May 3, 1801, and memo about the lands, ca. 1804, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 88
    - Letter from Jonathan Fisher to Eliphalet Pearson about College land in Blue Hill, with hand-drawn map of the area, April 24, 1804, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 89
    - Eliphalet Pearson’s memorandum about College land in Blue Hill, ca. 1804, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 90
      Includes a sketched plan of the lot.
    - Letter from Abijah Warren to the Harvard Overseers regarding purchase of Paris land, Jan. 10, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 91
    - Letter from John Heard, Jr., on behalf of Thomas Barker, to George Storer, regarding Barker’s wish to purchase Brownfield land, Jan. 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 92
      The letter was presumably intended for Ebenezer Storer.
    - Letter from Andrew R. Giddings to Jonathan Jackson about land in unspecified location, March 25, 1807, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 93
    - Letter from John Phillips, Jr. to Jonathan Jackson about Daniel Holden’s wish to buy Waterford land, July 2, 1807, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 94
      Verso contains various annotations, including an indication that Holden purchased the Waterford land in Nov. 1808.
    - Letter from Lothrop Lewis to Jonathan Jackson about Waterford land, July 15, 1807, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 95
    - Letter from Lothrop Lewis to Jonathan Jackson about Harrison and Waterford lands, Nov. 9, 1807, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 96
    - Letter from Jonathan Jackson to H.G. Otis about Otisfield land, Nov. 8, 1808 and Otis’s response, Nov. 7, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 97
      Otis wrote a response directly on Jackson’s letter; the date of Otis’s response is presumably incorrect, as it is earlier than the date Jackson wrote the original letter.
    - Memorandum regarding Jeptha Coburn’s wish to purchase New Sharon land, Feb. 2, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 98
    - Letter from Orren(?) Guild to Jonathan Jackson regarding payment (for surveying work?), March 7, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 99
    - Harvard Corporation vote authorizing appointment of agents to assess and sell “Eastern” lands, March 7, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 100
    - Manuscript copy of letters from Jonathan Jackson to David Cobb, Nicholas Tillinghast, Arthur Bradman, Thomas Perley, and Samuel Pomeroy regarding “Eastern” lands, April 13-July 20, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 101
    - Memorandum regarding “Eastern” lands, Aug. 31, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 102
    - Letter from Lothrop Lewis to Jonathan Jackson about appraisal of Otisfield and Waterford lands, Feb. 6, 1810, UAI 15.750 Box 2, Folder 103
    - Memorandum about trespassers on College lands, Feb. 4, 1818, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 1
      Memorandum is written on the verso of a letter from T. Dawes to John Davis.
    - Letter from Jeremiah Bailey to Josiah Stebbins about trespassers on Wiscasset land, Feb. 8, 1819, and letter from Josiah Stebbins to John Davis, Feb. 11, 1819, enclosed with Bailey’s letter, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 2
    - Letter from Jonathan Fisher to John Davis about value of Blue Hill land, Oct. 17, 1819, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 3
    - Letter from Jeremiah Bailey to John Davis about Dresden and Wiscasset lands, Oct. 30, 1819, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 4
    - Letters from Samuel M. Pond to John Davis about the value of Blue Hill and Orland lots, March 27, 1820 and Sept. 29, 1820, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 5
    - Letter from H.G. Otis to John Kirkland, Jan. 10, 1822, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 6
      Otis wrote to advise Kirkland regarding the issuing of bonds for lands in Maine.
    - Letter from Samuel M. Pond to John Davis about Orland land, April 20, 1822, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 7
    - Letter from Samuel Little to John Davis about Orland land, Sept. 13, 1824, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 8
    - Letters from Rufus K. Porter to John Davis about Machias land, July 26, 1824 and Nov. 29, 1824, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 9
    - Letter from Jonathan Fisher to John Kirkland about Blue Hill land, March 14, 1825, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 10
    - Bond of President and Fellows of Harvard College to Joseph G. Swan for sale of Blue Hill lot, and Swan’s cancelled notes, Jan. 1, 1826, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 11
    - Letters from John G. Deane to Thomas Wren Ward about Maine lands, Sept. 15, 1830 and Dec. 15, 1830, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 12
    - Letter from John G. Deane to Thomas Wren Ward about Maine lands, Oct. 24, 1831, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 13
    - Letter from John G. Deane to Thomas Wren Ward about Orland land, Jan. 10, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 14
      Letter is written on a document that was formerly a deed for Maine lands, created in 1833 but crossed out and marked as “cancelled.”
    - List of “Eastern” settlements, undated, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 15
    - Memorandum about Otisfield land, undated, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 16
    - Offers to purchase College lands in Bridgton, Baldwin, Bucksport, Flintstown, and Fryeburg, undated, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 17
    - Outer wrapping from bundle of Eastern Lands papers, undated, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 18
  - F. Lottery lands, 1787-1835
    In an effort to benefit financially from Massachusetts' land holdings in Maine, the General Court established a land lottery in 1786. In this lottery, all individuals who purchased a ticket - priced at £60 each - would received a lot of land, although some tickets corresponded to more desirable lots than others. Although 2,720 tickets were printed, only several hundred sold; Harvard was among the purchasers. Records in this subseries pertain to Harvard's purchases through the land lottery, held in the fall of 1787, and include lists of the lands drawn, lottery tickets, a chart, correspondence, and a memorandum.
    - List of lands belonging to Harvard, drawn in the land lottery, Oct. 12, 1787, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 19
    - Land lottery tickets (No. 1902-1911), May 20, 1788, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 20
      Tickets are signed by John Avery, Jr. (Secretary of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts) and Rufus Putnam and Leonard Jarvis, Managers.
    - Chart listing lottery lands owners, including township, number, and size of each lot, ca. 1788, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 21
    - Letter from Charles Turner to John Davis about lottery lands, Oct. 28, 1824, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 22
    - Letter from Joseph Morton to Francis Amory about lottery lands, Nov. 29, 1826, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 23
    - Manuscript copy of letter from the Harvard Treasurer’s office to Charles Turner about lottery lands, Sept. 27, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 24
    - Memorandum about location of lottery lands, June 10, 1835, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 25
  - G. Turner, 1787-1808
    Records in this subseries concern Harvard-owned lots in Turner, Maine, and include correspondence, notes about the lots, a memorandum, and several inhabitants' proposals to lease the lots.
    - Letter from William Turner to Ebenezer Storer about College lots in Turner, April 11, 1787 and memorandum about value of land, ca. 1787, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 26
    - Letter from Arthur Bradman to Ebenezer Storer requesting lease of Turner lot, Feb. 25, 1793, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 27
    - Suggested lease (unsigned) submitted by Arthur Bradman, Feb. 25, 1793, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 28
    - Certificate of Turner lots belonging to Harvard, written by town clerk William Turner, June 1, 1795, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 29
    - Eliphalet Pearson’s notes on Turner lots, based on information from Charles Turner, May 12, 1801, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 30
    - Letter from Arthur Bradman to Simeon Howard requesting purchase or lease of Turner lot, May 20, 1801, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 31
    - Letters from Charles Turner to Eliphalet Pearson about Turner lots, Oct. 1, 1801 and Oct. 26, 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 32
    - Letter from Arthur Bradman to Ebenezer Storer requesting purchase or lease of Turner lot, May 10, 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 33
    - Letter from Arthur Bradman to Paul Revere regarding his fear of eviction, May 21, 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 34
    - Memorandum regarding appraisal and sale of Turner lots, ca. March 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 35
      Addendum made in Feb. 1809.
    - Elisha Swetzen(?) Jr.’s proposal to lease a lot in Turner, undated, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 36
  - H. Fryeburg and Livermore, 1796-1809
    Records in this subseries pertain to Harvard-owned land in Fryeburg and Livermore; it should be noted that Livermore was apparently used interchangeably with Leeds, a town now located about ten miles away, at the time these records were created. Although Livermore and Fryeburg are not geographically close, a significant number of the records in this subseries pertain to both towns, so it was decided to group them together. Records include correspondence, a lease, memoranda, an appraisal, and a bond.
    - Note from Joseph Willard to Ebenezer Storer about College lands in Fryeburg, June 11, 1796, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 37
    - Rough draft of vote permitting Jesse Walker to cultivate the College land at Fryeburg, ca. 1796?, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 38
      Also includes notations about other individuals interested in cultivating the land.
    - Rough draft of vote appointing Daniel Farrington in charge of Fryeburg lot, ca. 1796?, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 39
    - Letter from Simon Frye to Eliphalet Pearson about College lands in Lovell, Fryeburg, and Brownsfield, June 13, 1801, and detailed descriptions of the lots, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 40
    - Letter from Elijah Livermore to Ebenezer Storer about Livermore lot, Sept. 13, 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 41
    - Eliphalet Pearson’s memorandum about College lands in Livermore, ca. 1805, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 42
    - Letter from Simon Frye to Ebenezer Storer about Oliver Knight’s wish to buy land in Fryeburg, May 17, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 43
    - Memoranda about Ziba Knap and Stilman Howard’s wishes to buy Livermore lots, Dec. 1806?, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 44
    - Memorandum about Seth Howard’s report of timber stolen from Livermore lot, Jan. 1807, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 45
    - Letters from Seth Howard to Jonathan Jackson about Livermore and Leeds lots, April 1, 1807; Aug. 17, 1807; and Oct. 19, 1807, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 46
    - Statement of Phillip Leach’s interest in buying Livermore land, transmitted by Joseph Lamson, Jan. 19, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 47
    - Letter from Lothrop Lewis to Jonathan Jackson about the value of Livermore lands, Jan. 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 48
    - Manuscript copy of letter from Jonathan Jackson to Lothrop Lewis about Fryeburg and Livermore lands, Feb. 27, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 49
    - Memorandum about Seth Howard’s purchase of Leeds land, March 1, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 50
    - Lothrop Lewis’ appraisal of land in Fryeburg and Livermore, May 18, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 51
    - Letter from Daniel Noyes to Jonathan Jackson, Feb. 23, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 52
    - Letter from Jonathan Jackson to Mr. Blanchard about bond for Oliver Knight, Feb. 27, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 53
    - Bond of President and Fellows of Harvard College to Oliver Knight and Daniel Noyes, Feb. 28, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 54
    - Letter from Seth Howard to Jonathan Jackson about Livermore lands, April 19, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 55
    - Jonathan Jackson’s receipt for bond borrowed from Oliver Knight and Daniel Noyes, June 1, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 56
  - I. Bucksport, 1801-1835
    Records in this subseries pertain to a Harvard-owned lot in Bucksport (alternately called Buckstown and Buckston), about 300 acres in size. The bulk of these records is correspondence, most of it related to a decades-long dispute among three brothers-in-law over the title to portions of the Bucksport lot. These three men, Moses Stubbs, Reuben Stubbs, and Nathan Smith, became engaged in various disputes over the land and often asked for the Harvard Treasurer to mediate or intervene. Also included are memoranda, articles of agreement, deeds, a bond, and a plan and appraisal of the land.
    - Letters from Stephen Peabody to Eliphalet Pearson about College land in Bucksport, June 4, 1801; June 22, 1801; and Aug. 21, 1801, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 57
      In June 22 letter, Peabody explains Moses Stubbs’ interest in buying the land. In Aug. 21 letter, Peabody also describes the College land in Orland.
    - Letters from Stephen Peabody to Eliphalet Pearson about College land in Bucksport, Jan. 19, 1802; Aug, 12, 1802; and March 28, 1803, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 58
      Peabody wrote on behalf of Moses Stubbs and Nathan Smith, in regards to their interest in purchasing the land.
    - Letters from Nathan Smith to Eliphalet Pearson about College land in Bucksport, Nov. 12, 1802 and Feb. 21, 1803, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 59
    - Eliphalet Pearson’s memorandum about College land in Busksport, ca. 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 60
    - Articles of agreement between Nathan Smith and the President and Fellows of Harvard College about Bucksport land, May 12, 1803, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 61
      Signed by Nathan Smith, Ebenezer Storer, Hannah Storer, and Susan Storer.
    - Letters from Nathan Smith to Ebenezer Storer, Aug. 2, 1804; Nov. 16. 1805; and Feb. 12, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 62
      Smith was having difficulty paying what he owed for the Bucksport land.
    - Letter from Eliphalet Pearson to Ebenezer Storer about the Bucksport lot, March 26, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 63
    - Reuben Stubb’s deed for portion of Bucksport lot, sold by Nathan Smith, May 19, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 64
    - Manuscript copy of articles of agreement between Moses Stubbs and Reuben Stubbs, and deed of Bucksport lot to Reuben Stubbs, May 19, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 65
    - Bond of Nathan Smith to Samuel Little, July 2, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 66
      Smith agreed to sell Little 1/6 of the Bucksport lot; bond is signed by Nathan Smith, Asa Peabody, and John Stubbs.
    - Letter from Stephen Peabody to Ebenezer Storer about dispute between Nathan Smith and Moses Stubbs, July 11, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 67
      Smith and Stubbs, who were brothers-in-law, were having difficulties related to the Bucksport land. Smith threatened to sell Moses’ portion, on which he’d built a valuable barn. Peabody asked Storer to create a deed for Moses, without the intermediary of Smith, who he deemed untrustworthy.
    - Letter from John Davis to Ebenezer Storer about Smith/Stubbs dispute, July 19, 1806, and manuscript copy of letter from Storer to Nathan Smith, July 19, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 68
    - Letter from Nathan Smith to Ebenezer Storer, July 27, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 69
    - Letter from Moses Stubbs to Ebenezer Storer, July 28, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 70
    - Deed of Bucksport lot to Nathan Smith from Harvard College, Aug. 7, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 71
    - Agreement between Ebenezer Storer, Nathan Smith and Moses Stubbs concerning Bucksport land, Aug. 30, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 72
    - Manuscript copy of Nathan Smith’s deed to Bucksport lot, ca. Aug. 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 73
    - Mediators’ findings in Smith/Stubbs dispute, Sept. 23, 1806 and letter from Moses Stubbs to Ebenezer Storer, Nov. 10, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 74
      Thomas Sparhawk and Caleb Hall acted as “referees” (mediators) in the case between Smith and Stubbs. They heard both sides of the story and found in favor of Stubbs, who enclosed their report in his letter to Storer, requesting a deed for his portion of the land in Bucksport.
    - Letter from P. Thacher to Ebenezer Storer, Dec. 5, 1806, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 75
      Thacher had apparently formerly acted as Nathan Smith’s representative, but wrote to explain that he no longer represented him.
    - Letter from Abner Rogers to Jonathan Jackson, inquiring about Bucksport land, April 2, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 76
    - John Davis’ receipt of payment from Moses Stubbs, July 19, 1816, and Moses Stubbs’ deed of gift of Bucksport land to his son, James Stubbs, July 20, 1818, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 77
      Annotation on verso indicates additional payment, received Oct. 2, 1817.
    - Letter from Reuben Stubbs to John Kirkland, Nov. 15, 1817 and petition of Reuben Stubbs to the Harvard Corporation, Nov. 17, 1817, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 78
    - Letters from Samuel M. Pond to John Davis, Dec. 13, 1817 and Feb. 1818, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 79
      Pond was Moses Stubbs’ lawyer, and was writing to let Davis know that Moses was suing his brother, Reuben, for trespassing.
    - Letter from Moses Stubbs and James Stubbs to John Davis about lawsuits related to Bucksport land, March 30, 1818, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 80
    - Letter from Reuben Stubbs to John Davis, Oct. 28, 1818, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 81
    - Letter from Samuel Little to John Davis about the disputes over Bucksport land, Dec. 5, 1818, UAI 15.750 Box 3, Folder 82